哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone I am Wang Gang
本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
Today's video we'll share a home recipe
开胃青椒
Pickled peppers appetizer
首先我们准备适量的二荆条去掉辣椒蒂之后备用（约1000克）
First prepare some Er Jing Tiao (green cayenne pepper cultivar), remove the stems and set aside.
二荆条在四川是比较常见的一种辣椒
Erjingtiao is more common in Sichuan
且辣度微辣比较香
It's mildly spicy, and more fragrant
湖南椒和四川二荆条外形酷似但只辣不香
Hunan pepper looks like Erjingtiao, but it is just spicy, not fragrant
然后准备适量的小米辣去蒂备用
Prepare some Xiaomi peppers (capsicum frutescens, pepper cultivar), remove the stems and set aside
小米辣的味道比较冲不能吃辣的同学请慎重
Xiaomi pepper is a bit stronger, if you can't eat spicy do without
原料准备好之后盆中加入适量的清水清洗干净
After preparing the previous ingredients, rinse them in a mixing bowl with clean water
因为是直接浸泡食用所以同学们最好多清洗几遍
Since they (the peppers) will be directly eaten after soaking, it is better to rinse thoroughly a few times
辣椒清洗干净之后捞出沥干水份备用
After rinsing the peppers, dry them out, and set aside
此菜从这里开始全程都不能再沾生水否则容易拉肚子
For this dish, from this point forward do not taint with unboiled water, otherwise you may get food poisoning
然后将辣椒斜刀切成小段备用
Then slice the erjingtiao peppers into small sections at an angle
同学们也可以带上手套用手撕成小条腌制
You can also put on some gloves to tear them into small pieces by hand for pickling
再将小米辣对半切开备用
Then cut the xiaomi peppers in half and set aside
吃不了辣的同学可以换成大红椒或者甜椒
If you can't eat spicy, feel free to substitute with red or orange bell peppers
准备适量的大蒜切成蒜片备用
Slice some garlic into slices and set aside
加入大蒜之后会有一股特殊的香味
After adding garlic, there will be a unique aroma
不喜欢大蒜的同学可以将其换成仔姜
If you don't like garlic, feel free to substitute with ginger roots
刀工不好的同学也可以对半切开
If you have poor knife technique, you can just slice them in half
大蒜切好之后放入盆中
After preparing the garlic, put them in the mixing bowl
下一步开始制作
Next step is to put it all together
首先我们在盆中加入适量的食用盐
First add salt to the mixing bowl
同学们盐的量可以稍微多一些这样才够味
Friends, feel free to add more salt for a stronger flavor and taste
再加入适量的白糖
Next add some sugar
白糖和盐的比例是1.5比1
The ratio of sugar to salt should be 1.5 to 1
然后将辣椒抓拌均匀腌制60分钟备用
Then use your hands to mix the peppers evenly, set aside to soak for 60 minutes
这60分钟辣椒和盐糖会发生一些反应
During these 60 minutes, the peppers will react with the salt and sugar
腌制辣椒出的水会有一些粘稠
The resulting extruded pickling liquid will be a bit thick and sticky
属于正常现象同学们不必担心
This is normal, friends don't worry
辣椒腌制60分钟之后放入坛中
After soaking for 60 minutes, put it in a pickling jar
只要是可以密封的容器也可以
As long as the jar is sealable, it'll be fine
同学们也可以放入盆中直接用保鲜膜封口
Friends you can also put it in a mixing bowl and cover it with clear wrap.
最后把剩下的辣椒水一起倒入
Finally pour in the rest of the pepper liquid
下一步开始制作料汁
Next we will prepare the seasoning
首先我们在锅中加入清水300克
First add 300g clean water to the wok
加入适量的鲜花椒
Add in some fresh Sichuan pepper
没有鲜花椒的同学也可以用青花椒代替
If you don't have fresh Sichuan pepper, substitute with green Sichuan pepper
加入白醋200克
Add 200g white vinegar
加入生抽酱油300克
Add 300g light soy sauce
然后开大火烧开
Then boil till dry on high heat
这一步的目的是样料汁融合煮出花椒的香味
The goal of this step is to combine the sauces with the Sichuan pepper and bring out its fragrance
大火烧开之后再关火冷却备用
After the boiling is done, cool and set aside
料汁冷却之后再倒入容器里面
Once the sauce has cooled, pour into the pickling container
最后盖上盖子将辣椒腌制3天左右
Finally put the cover on and let the peppers pickle for about 3 days
中途需要将辣椒翻一翻方便入味
Halfway through the pickling process, stir it around to ensure even flavor penetration
一道开胃青椒就制作完成
One order of pickled peppers appetizer is thus complete
下面开始技术总结
Next we will start the technical summary
第一，辣椒的辣度需要根据个人口味来选择
First, the spiciness should be catered to personal preferences
第二，糖的比例要比盐多一些，这样是为了中和辣味而非增加甜味
Second, there should be a larger amount of sugar versus salt, this is to balance out the spiciness, not to add additional sweetness
第三，料汁的比例为清水1.5，酱油1.5，白醋1.0再加上适量的花椒
Third, the sauce ratio should be: water 1.5, soy sauce 1.5, vinegar 1.0, then add a bunch of Sichuan pepper
第四，青椒做好之后的第二天和第三天都需要翻动一下方便入味
Fourth, on day 2 and 3 of the pickling process, be sure to flip the pickles to ensure even flavor penetration
开胃青椒的技术总结完毕
Pickle pepper appetizer technical summary complete
关注"西瓜视频美食作家王刚"
Subscribe to Gourmet Chef Wang Gang
这里总有一款属于你的菜
Where there will always be a dish for you